欢迎来到 Googleplex
LAURENCE MORONEY: Welcome to the Googleplex.
这是一个每天都能和一些优秀员工
This is an incredible place with lots of great stuff being
交流的奇妙地方
worked on every single day.
在我还没来这工作之前
Before I worked here, I always wondered
我总是在想，要是能来到 Googleplex 该多好
what it'd be like to come to the Googleplex,
和 Googler 们面面基，喝喝咖啡
meet up with a Googler, and have coffee with them.
聊聊他们在都干什么，是如何做的，为什么要做这个
And just chat about what they do, how they do it, and why they do it.
今天梦想成真了
And today we're going to do exactly that.
欢迎来和 Googler 喝咖啡
LAURENCE MORONEY: Welcome to Coffee with a Googler.
我是 Laurence Moroney，我在纽约城
I'm Laurence Moroney and I'm here in New York City
和 Roman Nurik 聊聊天
to meet with Roman Nurik.
Roman Nurik 是 Google Material Design 的大牛
And Roman Nurik is one of our material design gurus here at Google.
谈道 Material Design，告诉我们它是干什么的吧
So material design, tell me what's it all about.
好的，Laurence
ROMAN NURIK: Oh, Laurence.
什么是 Material Design
What is material design?
这有点难解释
It's kind of hard to explain.
实际上原来有一个视频
There's actually a video with a bunch of the original designers
讲的是 Material Design 的设计师们
that created material design and they
他们也同样被问到这个问题，也不知道该如何回答它
get asked the same question and they don't know how to answer it.
这说起来还蛮复杂
It is a complex kind of thing.
涉及到很多事情
There's a lot of things going on.
首先从最基本的层面讲，它是一门设计语言
I guess is the most basic level, it's a design language.
也是一个设计系统
It's a design system.
涵盖视觉交互以及动作行为设计
It covers visual interaction and motion design.
我觉得大多数设计系统以及设计语言
I feel like most design systems, design languages,
都统归于视觉语言
are treated as just visual languages.
比如你该用哪种颜色等等
Like here are the colors you should use, and so on.
但 Material Design 可不止这些
But material is much more than that.
它涵盖很多模型
It really kind of covers the model,
潜在的物理模型以及 UI 模型
the underlying physical model, of the UI.
所以它实际上是试图创建一个
So it basically tries to establish
适合你应用生存的一个物理环境
this physical environment within which your apps should live.
在手机、平板、桌面设备，以及任何的屏幕上
On a phone, on a tablet, on a computer, basically any sort of screen.
它创建这个物理环境
And then it basically establishes this physical environment and a set
并且建立了相关的规定和原则
of basic rules and principles.
我习惯把这个总结为四个轴
And I like to think of it along these kind of four basic axes,
或者说是四个基本原则
or four basic principles.
这是个形象的比喻
And that's tangible surfaces.
对于 Material 来说
Work on the material metaphor.
这样我们就能具体的谈谈 Material 是什么了
We can talk about what material is at some point.
也是一次大胆的平面设计尝试
Also bold graphic design.
我们应该从印刷的世界里学学一些优秀设计灵感
This idea that we should take some of the best design ideas
看看它们是如何帮助我们
from the print world and see how they can help us make really
在电子设备上创造出优秀的应用的
great apps on digital devices.
第三个则是关乎有意义的动效
And the third is meaningful motion.
如何把这些东西，这些平面
Basically how all these things, how these surfaces,
以及平面上的组件，图形设计元素
and the ink on that surface, the graphic design stuff,
协调起来
how that all moves in a consistent way to help
促进交互沟通
communicate what's going on.
第四件事,也是最重要的一件事情之一
And the fourth thing, which is to me one of the most important
则是适应性设计
things, is adaptive design.
这也是为什么我们能让前面提到的那三项
Which is how can we take all these first three things
能够正常协同工作的奥妙
and make sure that they work consistently
跨越不同的设备、手机和平板
and coherently across different devices, phones and tablets,
以及其他
and everything else.
正好这有一个视频
LAURENCE MORONEY: Now you have a video, right,
上面有一些优秀的 Material Design 运用实例
of some really good examples of material design being used.
我们给大家放一遍？
So should we roll that?
好的
ROMAN NURIK: Let's roll it.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
这真是足够优秀的实例啊
LAURENCE MORONEY: So some pretty excellent examples there,
但是问题是，有人能到达那个高度吗
but it's like, "How does somebody reach that level?"
拿我来说，我是一个开发者
And for someone like me, I'm a developer
我的设计技能几乎为零
and my design skills are nonexistent.
所以我想成为那个可以运用 Material Design
So if I want to become somebody who
来开发应用的人，我该如何开始？
can build apps with those kind of design, how do I get started?
我也要学这个吗？
How do I learn this stuff?
这是一个好问题
ROMAN NURIK: That's a great question.
首先，我来设想下
I think first of all, I just want to, I guess,
这些应用的背后它们都在做着出色的工作
recognize some of those apps they're doing amazing jobs.
它们可能有一个比较大的团队
And they have large teams, some of them
或者是小团队
actually have very small teams.
有些应用甚至是个人开发者开发的
Some of those apps are created by one person.
所以你是绝对可以达到那个高度
So you can absolutely reach that level of quality
来开发那些出色的应用的，不管你的团队有多小
from these amazing showcase apps regardless of your team size.
但是我想对开发者和设计师说的是
But I'd say for the developers and designers
这一切才刚刚起步
out there that are just getting started,
仍有大量的资源可以利用
there are a lot of great resources out there.
在 Udacity 上也有不少课程
There's a great Udacity course that me, Nick Butcher, also
由 Nick Butcher 和我以及 Udacity 的 James Williams 共同录制
from Google team here, and James Williams from Udacity put together.
你可以通过访问 udacity.com/google 来获取
And that's available at udacity.com/google.
同样在 design.google.com 上
And there's also a bunch of amazing resources
也有更多的资源在等着你
on design.google.com which will tell you
它会指导你如何在 Android 使用 Material Design
about how to come to Android if you're doing iOS stuff, for example.
如果是搞 iOS 方向的话,你可以了解一下 Material Design 是什么
Or how to get started understanding what material design is.
那里有 Material Design 的全部指导原则
Obviously the entire material design guidelines are there.
从观看 Udacity 的课程开始
So I'd say that's the first thing the Udacity
应该是新手起步的最佳选择
course is probably the best first step in getting started.
那里有大量资源
But there's a whole lot of resources out there
我们也那里做了其他资源的链接
and we link to others from the Udacity course.
谈到 Udacity 课程
LAURENCE MORONEY: And Udacity courses,
如果你还没听说过的话
if you're not familiar with them,
它们采用问答式的教学方法
they're very Socratic in how they teach.
通过短视频来让你挑战某件事情
It's short videos and then challenging you to do something.
然后再来一个短视频教你起步做这件事
And then a short video and then getting you to do something.
总之这是一个让人快速学习的好方法
And it's a good way to someone can incrementally
而不是把你扔进巨大的设计文档堆里
learn rather than be thrown into a huge design doc
或者类似的事
or something like that.
毫无疑问,这样进展显著
ROMAN NURIK: Yeah it's definitely-- there's a very clear progression.
我们特别地安排了那门课程
We specifically designed that course
你可以从了解一些基础知识开始
so that you can kind of start with some of the basics.
关于屏幕上的一些基础知识
The most elementary basic things about a screen,
比如说什么是像素,什么是独立像素密度
like what is a pixel, what is a density independent pixel.
之后水到渠成的你就能知道
And then you ramp all the way up to how
我该怎样把这个运用到手机,平板,以及其它设备上
do I make everything work on phones, tablets, and so on.
我就假设这些设计课程都是经过精心设计的了
LAURENCE MORONEY: And I have to assume that design course is
well designed.
我们在 Slide 和绘画板里
ROMAN NURIK: We have some very nice color
也做了一些非常棒的颜色选择
choices in our slides or our tablet drawings, so hopefully.
让我们再次回到 Material Design 话题
LAURENCE MORONEY: So back to material design again.
为什么是 Material
Why material?
谈到 Material 就回到刚才说的第一个原则了
ROMAN NURIK: So material goes back to that first principle.
也就是具有实体属性的平面
So this idea of tangible surfaces.
这意味着屏幕上的一切
This idea that everything on your screen and your device
都在其中的一个平面上
exists on a surface.
我们喜欢把它想象成一张纸
We like to think of them as pieces of paper.
你也可以看作是一片材料
So basically you can think of basically a sheet of material
或者说是表现在一张纸上
or the word material representing one of those pieces of paper.
我们不把叫它叫做纸是有原因的
And the reason we don't just call it
因为它不仅仅是一张纸
paper is because it actually is a lot more than just paper.
现实世界的纸张,一旦你把它撕碎
In the real world paper, once you rip it up
你就不能将其复原
you can't really just put it back together.
而且纸也不能从一个圆形变成一个正方形或者是矩形
And paper can't go from being a circle to a square to a rectangle.
所以我们将其看作是材料中的数字碎片
And so we like to think of our digital pieces of material,
或者是一片材料,一种智能的纸张
or sheets of material, as kind of a smarter paper.
仍是一种存在约束的纸张,你可以尽情使用
Still a constrained paper, you can just do anything.
但其也有缺憾
It can't just do all sorts of crazy things,
它只是在特定环境下存在的一种物理介质
but it is a physical thing that exists inside
在一种人造的特定环境
of this kind of environment, this kind of like faux environment.
依旧有很多的想法可以在上面付诸实践
But it is something that has a lot of thought put into it.
所以 Material 这个词对我来说是一片纸张
And so the word material to me really
里面可以容纳一些东西
means, the sheets of paper that everything in this world exists on.
对我来说真正要考虑的事情是
But for me is the main thing to think about,
动作在 Material Design 非常的重要
the reason that motion is so important in material design
一切的动效都应该是有意义的
is that motion should always have meaning.
尽量不要做这些动作，比如翻转一个按钮
Try not to just do it like a flip of a button,
或者是来一个双旋转
or like a double rotation, or something just
以及其他引起注意的动作
to kind of draw attention.
每一次的动作都会引起人们的注意
Every time something moves it attracts our attention
所以它应该变得有意义
and so it needs to be really thoughtful
需要小心翼翼的去设计
and really carefully planned out.
在 Material Design 中，我们可以利用足够的动作
And so in material, we use motion just enough motion
来传达物体的一些状态
to convey the change in some object's state
或者引起一些注意
or try to get a little bit of attention.
但是又不宜太多
But just enough motion not too little, not too much.
我知道 Android Studio有一些模板
LAURENCE MORONEY: I understand Android Studio has
允许开发者们在他们的 App 里
some templates to allow developers
融入 Material Design 风格
to at least get started with building material design into apps.
是的
ROMAN NURIK: Absolutely.
这也是我一直以来的人生观
So one of my philosophies for a long time has been,
我们创造出了 Material Design，或者说创造了一个东西
we can write about a material design, we can write about a thing.
我们可以针对这件东西给出很多建议
We can make suggestions about that thing.
我们可以告诉人们这个东西是干什么的
We can try to teach people about the thing.
但是最佳的方法是能让人们上手去做
But one of the best ways to get the thing into people's hands,
拿 Material Design 来说，我们就将其集成在了相关工具里
in this case material design, is to actually just build it
into the tools.
只要确保开发者们都能够上手
Just make sure that as a developer that's just getting
拿 Android 举例，无论我在 Android Studio 上
started, even just on Android, if I just
新建一个项目或者是一个 App
go to File, New Project or new app
我都能够用上最新、最棒的 Material Design
I should be able to get the latest and greatest.
所以我们在 Android Studio 中
And so in Android Studio, now we're
能看到很多 Material Design 模板
actually seeing new templates for material design.
你也可以创建一个新项目
So you could do file new project and then your default activity
默认的活动模板就是基于 Material Design 的
templates are going to come with material design in them.
现在就开始把 Material 主题用起来吧
So it's going to use the material theme.
这会利用一些新的 Material design 支持库
It's going to use some of the latest support
比如说 Android Design 支持库
libraries for material design, so things like the Android
AppCompat 之类的
Design Support Library, things like AppCompat,
你会免费得到一些超棒的东西
So you're just gonna get a lot of great stuff for free right
马上用起来
off the bat.
比如说我，我是一个程序猿不是设计师
LAURENCE MORONEY: So for someone like me, I'm a coder not a designer.
但是我可以用 Android Studio
But I could use Android Studio, get the effectively
用这些模板或者是脚手架来把这个问题解决掉
the scaffolding done for me in these templates.
然后也可以去 Udacity 上上课
And then learn from something like the Udacity course.
正解
ROMAN NURIK: Exactly.
我强烈安利你去 Udacity 上听听相关的课
I definitely suggest, even before you do the Udacity
新建一个项目
course, file new project.
看看相关代码
Just look around the code.
看看你的收获
See what you get.
我觉得这是一个很好的开端
I think that's a great way to get started.
实践是检验真理的唯一标准
I always valued as a kid growing up
learning programming and stuff I always valued experimentation.
而这正是实践
So definitely experiment with that.
如果你遇到什么障碍或者是困难的话
But as soon as if you hit an obstacle or something,
你可以看看教程以及相关的参考资料
obviously take a look at the guide and the reference, and all that.
再次安利一下 Udacity 的课程
But the Udacity course is a great way to say,
你知道吗，跟上 Google 的思考步伐
"You know what, let me just kind of see what Google thinks
是了解这个系统的最佳方式
is the right way to kind of approach understanding this system."
酷
LAURENCE MORONEY: Awesome.
感谢 Roman
Well thanks, Roman.
这是我今年学到的最有趣的
This has been a whole lot of fun and I've learned more about
关于 Material Design 的知识
material design in the last five minutes than I'd had in a year
再次感谢 Romen
before so thank you so much .
我能讲上一整天
ROMAN NURIK: I can always talk about this stuff.
他们跟我说了
LAURENCE MORONEY: They told me that about you.
这是我最爱谈论的话题
This is my favorite thing to talk about.
太酷了 Laurence
ROMAN NURIK: It's been awesome, Laurence.
感谢
Thanks.
我要去  Udacity 上瞧瞧相关课程
LAURENCE MORONEY: I'm going to check out that Udacity course
也推荐大家去看一看
and I recommend that you do so too.
如果你是 Android 开发者想了解一下这些模板的话
And if you're an Android developer take a look at those templates.
如果你仍对其抱有疑问
If you have any questions for me about this, or if you have
或者是关于 Material design 的
any questions for Roman about material design,
以及任何的 Material Design 相关
or other aspects of building for material design,
请在屏幕下方给我们留言
just please drop us a line in the comments below.
感谢收看本期的  Coffee with a Googler
Thank you for watching this episode of Coffee with a Googler.
更多精彩尽在 Coffee with a Googler
For more great episodes of Coffee with a Googler
想了解更多优秀的开发者专题
and for more great videos on the developer topics,
欢迎大家订阅 Youtube 上的 Google 开发者频道
please tune to the Google Developers channel on YouTube.
谢谢大家
Thank you.
[MUSIC PLAYING]